RG 169:007, Connecticut Forest and Park Association
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Forest and Park Association records
1883-2012
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Forest and Park Association
47 cubic feet
The Connecticut Forest and Park Association (CFPA) was founded on December 30, 1895, in Weatogue, Connecticut, at the home of Reverend Horace Winslow, as the Connecticut Forestry Association. In 1928, the Connecticut Forestry Association changed its name to the Connecticut Forest and Park Association. The name change reflected the association’s interest in recreation and leisure. Records include administrative files, minutes, correspondence, financial records, subject files, committee files, reports and studies, publications, press files, legislative files, Shaker Pines Corporation files, photographs, slides, scrapbooks, maps, artifacts, removable media, sound recordings, and film and video.
RG169_007
2013-020
Historical Note
The Connecticut Forestry Association, later named the Connecticut Forest and Park Association (CFPA), was founded by a group of concerned citizens who met at the Weatogue home of Reverend Horace Winslow on December 30, 1895. The association's founding coincided with a growing interest in conservation and forestry, driven in part by early environmentalists such as Theodore Roosevelt and Gifford Pinchot. The formal organization of the association occurred on Arbor Day in 1896 when a constitution and statement of purpose was adopted by the members.
The early history of the association was intertwined with the Yale Forestry School founded in 1900. The association from 1906-1927 had its office in Sage or Marsh halls on the Yale campus. Forestry School professors and graduates such as Henry Graves, President, 1906-1909; Vice President, 1922-1924; and Director 1928-1931; Austin Hawes, Director, 1906-1909 and 1943-1944; and David M. Smith, President, 1975-1981; Director 1963-1974 and 1981-2004; were all active leaders and members in the association's programs.
In 1928, the Connecticut Forestry Association changed its name to the Connecticut Forest and Park Association. The name change reflected the association's interest in recreation and leisure. Throughout the first half of the twentieth century, the CFPA participated in the establishment of the state park system. The CFPA and its early members were crucial in the acquisition of the Peoples State Forest; Mohawk State Forest; Talcott Mountain; Gillette Castle; and state parks such as Hammonasset, Sherwood Island, Rocky Neck, Bluff Point, and Sleeping Giant.
The Blue-Blazed Hiking Trail system, which would become a signature initiative of the CFPA, was established on October 5, 1929. Several years later, in 1937, the first Connecticut Walk Book was published as a guide to the hiking trail system. A key proponent of the Blue-Blazed Hiking Trails was Edgar L. Heermance who is commonly known as the "father of the Blue Blaze Trails". Heermance was Secretary of the CFPA from 1936-1948. He was succeeded by William C. Shepard, 1948-1952, who was in turn succeeded by Archibald W. Hurford, 1952-1963. In 1963, John E. Hibbard was hired as Secretary-Forester. This was the beginning of a fruitful partnership between Hibbard and the association. John Hibbard retired, after a full and successful career, in 2000. His successor Paul Wingle, 2001, served only briefly before resigning. Wingle was succeeded by Adam Moore, 2001-2008. Eric Hammerling, the incumbent Executive Director and Secretary, was appointed in May 2008.
The Connecticut Forest and Park Association has throughout its history established and participated in a variety of outreach activities. These include Connecticut Releaf, Connecticut Trails Day, Project Learning Tree, Walk CT and many more. The CFPA has a long history of lobbying the state government on issues such as the environment, forestry, wildlife, recreation, and trails. Funding and support for the Connecticut Department of Environmental Protection has been of particular interest over the years.
The association has maintained multiple headquarters. The original headquarters was located in New Haven from 1906-1956. In 1956 the association moved to Wallingford, then to Hartford from 1964-1968, and then to East Hartford from 1968-1986. In 1986 the CFPA moved to a newly constructed headquarters in Middlefield. The headquarters was named in honor of James L. Goodwin a previous President, 1954-1961, and Director, 1961-1966.
Scope and Content
The records are arranged into nineteen series which document the organization and activities of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association. The series include: Administrative Files, Minutes, Correspondence, Financial Records, Subject Files, Committee Files, Reports and Studies, Publications, Press Files, Legislative Files, Shaker Pines Corporation Files, Photographs, Slides, Scrapbooks, Maps, Artifacts, Removable Media, Sound Recordings, and Film and Video.
Series 1. Administrative Files, 1920-2010, consists of contacts, staff files and employment information. The series also contains a copy of the constitution and by-laws of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association, as well as additional governance documents.
Series 2. Minutes, 1923-2011, consists of meeting minutes, agendas, and notices from board meetings, the trails committee, and other committees.
Series 3. Correspondence, 1917-2010, contains correspondence of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association. The bulk of the material is from the Secretary-Forester, particularly John E. Hibbard and Adam Moore, and the executive committee.
Series 4. Financial Records, 1933-2012, contains audits, treasurer's reports and budgets and miscellaneous financial information.
Series 5. Subject Files, 1895-2010, consists of material on a wide variety of topics with the majority of material relating to a specific town, state park or trail.
Series 6. Committee Files, 1929-2011, consists of records from the Hiking Trails Committee. Most of the material relates to the status of various sections or trails.
Series 7. Reports and Studies, 1910-2010, contains reports done by and for the Connecticut Forest and Park Association. The majority of the reports concern forestry and conservation. Annual reports, development reports and various other reports concerning the Connecticut Forest and Park Association are also included.
Series 8. Publications, circa 1883-2011, includes a wide variety of publications, newsletters, and pamphlets relating to conservation and forestry. Of particular note is a complete set of Connecticut Woodlands, 1937-2011, and multiple editions of the Connecticut Walk Book.
Series 9. Press Files, 1898-2010, includes clippings, press bulletins and programs.
Series 10. Legislative Files, 1921-2009, consists of records, such as lobbying agendas, scorecards and correspondence, relating to the legislative efforts of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association.
Series 11. Shaker Pines Corporation Files, 1937-1942, consists of financial records and correspondence from the Shaker Pines Corporation. The bulk of the material relates to the winding down of the corporation.
Series 12. Photographs, 1900-2011, consists of photographs on the following topics: State Parks and Forests; trails; programs; Trails Day; workshops; events; clubs, associations and organizations; buildings; landscapes; exhibits and display materials; publication materials; logos; portraits; and photograph albums on various topics.
Series 13. Slides, 1907-2002, consists of slides on the following topics: State Parks and Forests; trails; programs; workshops; events; buildings; landscapes; exhibit materials; publication materials; collections; and duplicate groups of slides.
Series 14. Scrapbooks, circa 1921-1994, consists of newspaper clippings, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, booklets, and programs.
Series 15. Maps, 1929-1978, consists of hiking, isolines, and topographic maps.
Series 16. Artifacts, 1996, undated, includes a slide viewer, 35 mm film, badges, silver and blue ribbon, picture and word signs, and trail signs.
Series 17. Removable Media, 1994-2005, contains nine floppy disks and ten compact discs.
Series 18. Sound Recordings, 1966-1993, contains nine sound cassettes and seven reels.
Series 19. Film and Video, 1998, undated, contains four videocassettes (VHS) and one videocassette (U-matic).
Arrangement
Series 1. Administrative Files, 1920-2010
Series 2. Minutes, 1923-2011
Series 3. Correspondence, 1917-2010
Series 4. Financial Records, 1933-2012
Series 5. Subject Files, 1895-2010
Series 6. Committee Files, 1929-2011
Series 7. Reports and Studies, 1910-2010
Series 8. Publications, circa 1883-2011
Series 9. Press Files, 1898-2010
Series 10. Legislative Files, 1921-2009
Series 11. Shaker Pines Corporation Files, 1937-1942
Series 12. Photographs, 1900-2011
Series 13. Slides, 1907-2002
Series 14. Scrapbooks, circa 1921-1994
Series 15. Maps, 1929-1978
Series 16. Artifacts, 1996, undated
Series 17. Removable Media, 1994-2005
Series 18. Sound Recordings, 1966-1993
Series 19. Film and Video, 1998, undated
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Forest and Park Association
Subjects:
Forests and forestry -- Connecticut; Forests and forestry -- Societies, etc.; Parks -- Connecticut; Connecticut -- Guidebooks; Hiking -- Connecticut; Land use -- Connecticut; Trails -- Connecticut; Trees -- Connecticut; Outdoor recreation -- Connecticut; Connecticut Forest and Park Association -- Periodicals; Forests and forestry -- Connecticut -- Periodicals; Parks -- Connecticut -- Periodicals; Trails -- Connecticut -- Maps; Hiking -- Connecticut -- Maps
Places:
Connecticut; New Haven (Conn.); Middlefield (Conn.); Hartford (Conn.); East Hartford (Conn.); Wallingford (Conn.); Weatogue (Conn.)
Persons:
Buttrick, Philip L.; Chapman, Herman Haupt, 1874-1963; Goodwin, James L.; Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951; Hammerling, Eric; Hawes, Austin F. (Austin Foster), 1879-1962; Heermance, Edgar L.; Hibbard, John E.; Hurford, Archibald W.; Milne, George M.; Moore, Adam; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Ross, Robert M.; Shepard, William C.; Smith, David M., 1921-2009; Wingle, Paul; Winslow, Horace, 1814-1905; Woolsey, Theodore S.
Document Types:
Agendas; Clippings; Compact discs; Correspondence; Floppy disks; Maps; Minutes; Photographs; Pamphlets; Press releases; Financial records; Notebooks; Publications; Reports; Scripts (documents); Programs (documents); Scrapbooks; Brochures; Histories; Sound Recordings; Legal Documents; Videocassettes; Slides (photographs)
Restrictions on Access
Series 17. Removable Media, 1994-2005, is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Series 18. Sound Recordings, 1966-1993, is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Series 19. Film and Video, 1998, undated, is restricted. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
These records were donated by the Connecticut Forest and Park Association to the Connecticut State Library on December 17, 2012.
Container List
- Series 1. Administrative Files, 1920-2010
  - Agreements, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association articles of incorporation and by-laws, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution of the Connecticut Forestry Association, circa 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contracts, 1982-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copyright registration form, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Director appointments, 1957-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Director appointments, 1997-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Director resignations, 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Grant of conservation restrictions, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Grants, 2003-2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Job advertisements, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Library rules and regulations, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - List of Connecticut Forest and Park Association officers and directors, 1938-2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - List of official publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Membership, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nominations, 1941-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Planning documents, 1980-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Policies governing the acquisition of land and conservation restrictions, 1981-2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Preliminary employment handbook, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Resolutions, 1920-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Staff files, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series 2. Minutes, 1923-2011
  - Accounts of annual meetings, 1898-1902, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Annual meeting accounts were compiled using newspaper accounts under the direction of association secretary P. L. Buttrick
  - Annual business meeting minutes and reports, 1923-1930 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Minutes, 1931-1938 (Box 2, Folder 4-9)
  - Minutes, 1939-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1-49)
  - Minutes, 2001-2011 (Box 4, Folder 1-11)
  - Trails Committee meeting minutes, 1929-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - Trails Committee meeting minutes, 1975-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1-14)
  - Trails Committee meeting minutes, 2003-2011 (Box 5, Folder 15-20)
- Series 3. Correspondence, 1917-2010
  - Correspondence, 1917-1949; Includes information for Mrs. Riddle's bequest of Hill-Stead. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1951-2005 (Box 6, Folder 3-24)
  - Correspondence, 2006-2010 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
- Series 4. Financial Records, 1933-2012
  - Audits, 1963-2004 (Box 7, Folder 6-11)
  - Audits, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bankruptcy - chapter eleven documents, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cash receipts analysis and journal, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cash receipts journal, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cash disbursements journal, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Economic census, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Form 990 ratio analysis, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - General ledger report, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Grant administration, 1992-2006 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Payment and expense forms, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Portfolio holdings, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Promissory note, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Real estate transactions, 1959-2010 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - RWA finances, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Treasurer's reports and budgets, 1933-1975 (Box 7, Folder 26-45)
  - Treasurer's reports and budgets, 1976-2006 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
  - Treasurer's reports and budgets, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Series 5. Subject Files, 1895-2010
  - Addresses at dinner in honor of Austin F Hawes, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Archival project, 2003, 2007 June (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Avon parcel records, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Berlin parcel records, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Biblioscape reference manual, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bluff Point / Haley Farm, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Bluff Point State Park, 1984-1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Bridgeport, City of, 1972-1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Cathedral Pines, Cornwall Connecticut - storm damage, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Chapman, H. H. - articles, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Chapman, H. H. - papers regarding 1944-1945 Park and Forest Commission controversy (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Charcoal making, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Charter Oak, 1985-1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Charts and graphs, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Cockenoe Island - Westport, Connecticut, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Coltsfoot Farm - Cornwall, Connecticut, 1983-1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association headquarters, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association historical material, 1904-1924 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association history, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association illustrations, 1895-1927 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association logos, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association marketing material, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association miscellaneous, 1936-2004 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    Miscellaneous folder includes brochures, publications, memorial write up on William G. Shepard, "Future Importance of Leisure" diagram, The Kresge Foundation press release, CFPA 100 Year Talk list of attendance and sales figures, flyers, and address lists.
  - Connecticut Forest and Park Association - publications available in CFPA and Yale libraries, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Connecticut forestry history - notes, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Connecticut Greenways, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Connecticut / New York state line, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Connecticut Outdoor Recreation Guide - original copy, 1976; Photographs with the original copy removed to Series 12. Photographs. (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Connecticut Releaf, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Connecticut River Basin, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Connecticut River Highlands - new state park, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Connecticut, State of - Department of Environmental Protection - Environment 2000 (goals and management strategies), 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Department of Environmental Protection budget, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Durham parcel records, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Dutch Elm Disease, 1974-1993 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Earth Day 20, 1990, 1989-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - East Rock Park - New Haven, Connecticut, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit labels, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Farmington parcel records, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Forces of Nature by Stephen Most, sixth draft, 2007 September; 1 script (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Forest land enhancement program, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Forestry miscellaneous, 1949-2006 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Miscellaneous folder includes advertisements, articles, copies of minutes of the State Outdoor Education Committee, duplicate maps of Connecticut showing town boundaries, flyers, and stumpage price survey results.
  - Forrester and Tidd Associates, 1983-1994 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Fort Shantock, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Goodwin Forest Conservation Education Center, 1968-2006 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gillette Castle State Park, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Glastonbury, Town of, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Haddam parcel records, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Haley Farm State Park, 1965-1979 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
  - Haley Farm State Park, 1981-1996 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
  - Harkness Memorial State Park Arts Park Proposal, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hawes, Austin F., 1944-1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Heermance, Edgar L., 1935-1979 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Heermance, Edgar L. - Rocky Top, Hamden, Connecticut, 1987-2005 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Highway shade trees, 1926-1945 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - History of Connecticut forestry - SAF 1969-1970, 1969-1980 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Hubbard Park - Meriden, Connecticut, 1966-1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Hunting, 1993-2001 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Interstate 84, 1969-1982 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - James L. Goodwin Conservation Center, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Land preservation training program, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Leatherman, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - LLRW, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Madison / Guilford parcel records, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Marketing proposals, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Membership, 1933-1936, 1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Meriden parcel records, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Metacomet - Monadnock - Mattabesett, 2005-2009 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Middletown parcel records, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous logos, undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1920-1994 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous remarks, 1922-2004 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - National Wildlife Federation, 1993-2007 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - National Wildlife Federation new logo, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Natural areas, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Newman, Paul, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - New England Trail, 2007-2010 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - New Haven Hiking Club, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Newtown Forestry Association, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Notes on James L. Goodwin Conservation Center, 1964-1969 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Osbornedale State Park - Derby, Connecticut, circa 1972-2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Olmsted Legacy Trail, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Pageant - The Peoples Forest by Elliott P. Bronson, 1924; 1 script (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Phelps Property, North Colbrook, Connecticut, 2010 August 1 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Pinchot, Gifford, 1936-2007 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pinchot - Muir, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Potential closure of Metropolitan District Commission lands, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Power lines, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Questionnaires, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Riparian buffer zone, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Sample of Connecticut Forest and Park Association material, circa 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Folder includes pamphlets, brochures, donation card, membership form, environmental agenda, programs, newsletter, stationary, and stickers.
  - Sanford property appraisal, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Saugatuck Nature Trail, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Scantic River Valley State Park, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sherwood Island State Park, 1996-2002 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Silver Sands State Park - New Milford, Connecticut, 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Simsbury House, 1977-2000 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Simsbury parcel records, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Sleeping Giant Park Association, 1924-1944 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Sleeping Giant Park Association, 1932-1940 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Sleeping Giant Park Association, 1942-1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Southington parcel records, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Speaking engagements - Hibbard, John, 1982-1996 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - State forest articles, 1955-1972 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - State (Connecticut) parks, 1986-2000 (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - State park 75th birthday, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Stratton Brook State Park - regarding Red Pine salvage cut, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Summary of thoughts for board seminar, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Talcott Mountain, 1963-1994 (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1972-2005 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Talcott Mountain Project, 1963-1966 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Topsmead State Forest, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Town of Hebron, 1969-1993 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Trail notebooks, circa 2004-2009; 2 notebooks (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Trail notebooks, circa 2008-2010; 1 notebook (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Tree talk, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Triassic Basin - Connecticut and Massachusetts, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Tunxis, 1975-1986 (Box 10, Folder 35-36)
  - WalkConnecticut, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Western Connecticut Linear Park along Route 7, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - West Rock Ridge State Park, 1974-1995 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Wetlands, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Wood biomass, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Series 6. Committee Files, 1929-2011
  - Hiking Trails Committee, 1929-2011
    - Barkhamstead section, 1934-1942 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Bridgeport section, 1933-1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Bristol section, 1930-1948 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fairfield section, 1937-1940 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Glastonbury section, 1940-1947 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hartford section, 1929-1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Hartland section, 1937-1948 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Hiking trails committee, 1929-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8-23)
    - Hiking trails committee, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Hiking trails committee, 2006-2007 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Hiking trails committee, 2008-2011 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Litchfield section, 1929-1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Manchester section, 1946-1954 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Mattabesett and George Washington Trails, 1934-1947 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Mattabesett and Metacomet Trails - Meriden section, 1930-1953 (Box 12, Folder 6)